Shalom Bhooshi

https://shalomb.id os.bhooshi@gmail.com +421 948 140 290

Abstract

An adept DevOps professional with a background in the Agile and Continuous Delivery of cloud platforms and services. Combining 20 years experience in IT and engineering, I seek to apply myself in a setting that innovates technology and working practices to advance digital platforms.

Core Competencies

- Application of practical DevOps and Lean-Agile for Continuous Delivery of Platform Capabilities
- Cloud Solution design and implementation on private, public and hybrid cloud platforms
- Code-centric approach to managing Platform Services and Tooling (i.e. APIs, IaC, GitOps)

Skills

Agile PM DevOps, Lean-Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Design Thinking, EBM
Cloud Platforms Amazon EC2, Google Cloud, Canonical Openstack, Apache Cloudstack
Amazon AWS VPC, EC2, EBS, ELB, Route53, Cloudfront, Cloudwatch, S3, Glacier
Containerization docker, docker-compose, Kubernetes, Service Mesh essentials
Scripting Python, Bash, POSIX Shell, Go, Powershell
IaC Terraform, Ansible, CloudFormation, goss, Make
CI/CD git, Github, Gitlab CI, Travis CI, Scrutinizer CI, JFrog Artifactory
Observability Prometheus, Grafana, Graylog2, CloudWatch, New Relic, Nagios
Web nginx, envoy proxy, Cloudflare, Python Flask, HTTP, REST
Databases Postgresql, MariaDB, Elasticsearch, CouchDB, Redis, SQLite
Networking TCP/IP - IPv4 & IPv6, DNS, VPC/Network Design, VPNs, NetSec

Professional Experience

Takeda Innovation Capability Center • Bratislava, Slovakia • Pharmaceuticals

The Takeda ICC assembles cloud, data and digital capabilities for project demands within Takeda's business platforms to better serve Patient, Trust, Reputation and Business.

Jun 2022 → Present Cloud Engineering and DevOps Lead Engineer, ICC Cloud Chapter

- **Responsibilities** Supporting an engineering team responsible for the IaC implementation of DevOps and Cloud Enablement (DCE) project builds on AWS and ensuring their operational readiness.
 - Innovating on/Ensuring adherence to working practices, Improving team effectiveness, Managing technology radars, Conducting research spikes, Improving tools and processes,

• Taking on delegated responsibilities of the chapter lead - Chapter build-outs, Business Engagements, Resource Assignments, Technical Interviews, KPI reporting. Skills EBM, SAFe, Scrumban, AWS, IaC, Cloudformation, Terraform Accenture Technology Solutions - Slovakia • Bratislava, Slovakia • Enterprise Client Solutions Accenture ATCs are technology and innovation hubs for enterprise clientele providing digital technologies, programming, testing, technical architecture, DevOps, and service/programme management capabilities. Jan 2022 → May 2022 DevOps Lead, Global Travel & Expenses Platform assignment Responsibilities Supporting a team of 6 working to enhance the customer's IaC and CI/CD/CT profiles in preparation for an enterprise public cloud migration (Azure) project. Skills SAFe, Cloud Lift-and-Shift (IaC Consolidation), VMWare, Ansible/IaC, Scrumban Jul 2021 \rightarrow Jan 2022 DevOps Engineer/Architect, Image Automation AI/ML Accelerator assignment • Working in a team of 3 DevOps engineers within a cross-functional team Responsibilities Designing AWS IaC to requirements, Supporting ML workflows with automation, Designing continuous delivery pipelines, Evolving cloud security / cost optimizations. • Working on a technical architecture committee - Stakeholder Engagement, Architectural Decision Making, Backlog Engineering, Iteration Planning, Solution Design and Reviews. Skills Technology Ownership, AWS, IaC, Terraform, AWS CDK, Azure DevOps, DevOps, CI/CD/CT Deutsche Telekom Pan-Net • Bratislava, Slovakia • NFVi/Telco Cloud pan-net.cloud is a Deutsche-Telekom private cloud/IaaS platform designed to host specialized NFVi service lines and supporting general-purpose IT workloads for subsidiary european Telco operators. Jun 2019 → Present Cloud Infrastructure Engineer/Technical Lead, IT PaaS, Pan-Net Cloud Skills & Experience PaaS Solution Development, Technology Ownership, Stakeholder Engagement, Architecture Definition, Sprint Scheduling, Solution Exploration/Review/Presentation Feb 2018 \rightarrow May 2019 Cloud Infrastructure Engineer, NFVi DevOps, Pan-Net NFVi

Responsibilities DevOps of CI/CD services, Design of CI/CD pipelines for VNF lifecycles

Skills Agile Release Trains, Delivery Pipelines, DevOps, Gitlab CI, Artifactory, Openstack, Docker,

Skills Agile Release Trains, Delivery Pipelines, DevOps, Gitlab Cl, Artifactory, Openstack, Docker, Ansible, Linux, Terraform, Python, goss, Prometheus, Grafana

• _____

 $\mathbf{Aug}\ \mathbf{2017} \to \mathbf{Jan}\ \mathbf{2018}$ Cloud Infrastructure Engineer, Application Orchestration, Pan-Net NFVi

Responsibilities Development of VNF application lifecycle orchestrators

Skills Openstack, OpenContrail, Linux, Ansible, Python, OASIS TOSCA

Box+Dice (BDSK) • Bratislava, Slovakia • CRM/SaaS

Box+Dice are an Australian developer of products and services for real-estate B2B operations.

Oct 2015

Jun 2017 Senior Systems Engineer, Site Reliability Engineering

Responsibilities SaaS DevOps/SRE, Cloud Migration - Lift-and-shift, Cloud Optimization, Technical Security, CI/CD tools and infrastructure, Reporting to Executive Committee, Customer L3 Support

Skills Project Management, Amazon AWS, SRE/DevSecOps, Mentoring, Ansible, Terraform, bash, Python, Ruby, Cloudflare, Linux, Postgres, MariaDB, Elasticsearch

Citrix Systems UK Ltd • Cambridge, United Kingdom • Independent Software Vendor

Citrix solutions power enterprise data, workspace and mobility needs to create better ways to work.

 ${
m Jul~2010}
ightarrow {
m Aug~2015}$ Senior Software Test Engineer, Engineering Productivity, Desktop and Apps

Responsibilities DevOps/Architecture of Test-aaS platforms and services, Datacenter management - hardware procurement and maintenance, Push-button provisioning of Test Environments, Test framework/library development, Appliance/VM image creation/cataloguing

Skills Citrix Virtualization/DaaS, Private Cloud Architecture, IaaS/Virtualization, Network Design, Enterprise Software Testing, CloudStack, Xen/XenServer, PowerShell, Perl, Python

IT Freelancer • Greater London Area, United Kingdom • Various

 $\mathbf{Aug}\ \mathbf{2002} \ \rightarrow \ \mathbf{Dec}\ \mathbf{2007}\ \mathrm{IT}\ \mathrm{Freelancer},\ \mathrm{Various}\ \mathrm{Small/SOHO/Medium\text{-}sized}\ \mathrm{Businesses}$

Responsibilities Web development/authoring/mastering, Designing Office IT & connectivity solutions, Designing Network Solutions, Desktop Publishing, Support

Skills LAMP, Microsoft SMB Solutions, Microsoft Office, Cisco Routing/Switching, Firewall/VPNs, Perl, Shell Scripting

Education

Sep $2008 \rightarrow May 2010$ BSc (1:1, Hons.) Computer Networks, Sheffield Hallam University, Sheffield

Training and Qualifications

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, Currently Certifying
- Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA) 2020, Currently Certifying
- SAFe Practitioner, Feb 2022
- DevOps Institute DevOps Leader (DOL), Jan 2022

- Managing Distributed Teams, Nov 2021
- Docker + Kubernetes Administration, May 2018
- OpenStack Deployment and Advanced Administration, Feb 2018
- OpenStack Administration Bootcamp, Sep 2017
- Citrix NetScaler ADC Essentials, Networking and Administration, Jun 2012
- Building Scalable Cisco Internetworks (CCNP BSCI), Feb 2004
- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA), Mar 2003
- Implementing & Administering a Microsoft Directory Services Infrastructure, Apr 2003
- Implementing & Administering a Microsoft Network Infrastructure, Apr 2003

Professional Profiles

shalomb.id, Keybase, Github, Gitlab, StackOverflow Developer Story, Pluralsight, Linkedin

Spoken Languages

English (Native), French (High School/University), Slovak (Basic Vernacular)

Hobbies and Interests

Fatherhood \circ Road Cycling, Mountain Biking \circ Outdoors \circ Guitar, Music \circ Conversation

Personal Details

Telephone +421 948 140 290 Email s.bhooshi@gmail.com Date of Birth 8 Jan, 1983 Nationality British Residentship Slovak Permanent Residentship

Download

PDF Version shalom_bhooshi-cv.pdf Online Version shalomb.id/cv

Fork me on GitHub